We build sound systems, and screen printing, and illustration
僕らはサウンドシステムとシルクスクリーンを作っている それとイラストもね
but we used to do stuff all by hand we'd be working to like point 3, 4 of a mil
全て手作りでやってた。以前は3,4ミルの精度で、
and now we're working to like point 1 of a mil accuracy because we've got laser cutters
今は、0.1ミルの精度でやっている レーザーカッターを買ったんだよ
we've got all the cutting jigs and it is all cut with hand by routers, but
僕らは今までにあらゆる治具を手に入れてて、 それらはどれもルーターを使って手作業で切られてた
you're working from a template that you digitally produced
だけど、デジタル的に作ったテンプレートを 使って仕事をすると、
and then once you've got that template you've got it forever.
一度手に入れたテンプレートはずっと使用する事が出来る
Dave, you know, he's a proper old school carpenter joiner
デイヴは正しくオールドスクールな大工だ
Everything's done by hand, and all proper oak and teak and ash
全て手作業で作る。そして適切に選ばれた オークやチークやトネリコの木材を使う
and then we're in here, we're making speakers out of birch-ply and MDF
僕らはここでバーチ材やベニヤ、 MDFを使ってスピーカーを作っている
and furniture out of birch-ply and stuff like that
バーチ材で家具を作ったりとか。そういう感じだ
and we're using like, laser cutters and all that, and he's using
僕らはレーザーカッターとか、 そういった物を使用していて、
proper old school hand tools and stuff. And it's just really nice that it's side by side.
彼は適切に、オールドスクールの手作業の工具類を使っている そのどちらもあるということが、本当に良いんだ
You know you can't, you still need to have the hand tooling skills and stuff like that.
まだまだ手で工具を使用するようなスキルは必要だ
You've got to understand the intricacies of putting it together
それらを組み合わせる時の複雑さを理解する必要があるんだ
and how it goes together, and what bits you're going to need,
どのように組み合わさるか、どんなビットが必要になるか
and how to mix the hand skills with the CAD/CAM skills
どうやって手作業の技術と、CAD/CAMの技術を組み合わせるかもね
and when I went to school, I went to Uni at Salford, eight or nine years ago
8年か9年前、僕が学生だったころに、 ソルフォードにあったUniに行ったんだ
and they didn't have a laser cutter, they didn't have anything.
彼らはレーザーカッターどころか何も持ってなかった
They had a rapid prototyper which was the flour and water composite thing,
粉末と水を混ぜ合わせたような物で 素早くプロトタイプする機械を持っていて
like literally, you touched it and it went "PHOOOOSH" like that
さわったら、それはまさに、フーシュ（粉が飛び散る擬音） という感じだった
and it was good, but now here we are 9 years later and the school I used to teach in
それはそれで良かった。だけど、今は9年後だ そして僕が教えにいっていた学校は
used to have a dimension plotter, 3D Printer, like 2 laser cutters
ディメンジョンプロッターと、3Dプリンターを持っていた 2台のレーザーカッターとか
a CNC lathe, a CNC router and that's in the space of 9 years.
CNC旋盤や、CNCルーターなども。それらは9年前からそこに あったわけだけど
And then you've got 11, 12, 13 year old kids who do that type of thing
11歳から13歳の子供たちと一緒にいて、彼らはそこで
right from that age all the way through.
その歳からこういったことをやり始める事になる
think the thing that made me realize how good and powerful it could all be
それらが素晴らしく、パワフルな可能性を 秘めているという事に気づいたのは
was when I started learning how to use Illustrator.
イラストレーターの使い方を学んでいるときだったと思う
And it just made me go, all right! That was like a month ago taking me like a week to do.
僕はその道を選んだことに、オールライトだ！と思えたんだ なぜなら、それはまるで一ヶ月前に一週間かかった事が、
It's now taking me four hours. It just sort of made me go, huh, all right, yeah
今はたった４時間でできるようになるみたいな事なんだ それはまさに、オールライトだ！と思えた事だったんだ
it does make a lot of sense.
それには十分納得がいっている